

Dave Budd Software Engineer / Developer

O Bristol (UK)

& +44 77 966 944 32

daveisagit

SKILLS

Languages

🏓 Python 👙 Java 🗾 Javascript

Databases

🗣 Postgres BigQuery Oracle

MSSQL

Frameworks

dj Django Celery

Frontend

HTML/CSS & jQuery B Bootstrap

Cloud

△ GCP ⊗ Kubernetes Terraform

Integration / APIs

REST GraphQL SOAP

JMS

Deployment + CI/CD

Docker Kustomize Helm

Github

Actions Circle CI

EDUCATION

BSc Mathematics

University of Southampton

1987-1990

PGCE

Institute of Education 1990-1991

PROFILE

I have over 25 years experience of projects in various business sectors including Finance, Banking, Charity, Public Sector, Utilities and Logistics.

I primarily work in development roles but have also done Analysis, Design, Data Migration, Integration and DevOps. I have experienced a wide range of technologies and languages and I am proficient in picking up new ones very quickly.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Feb 2019 - Present

OVO Energy

- Helped decommission an outdated in-house FTP/MFT system.
- Created a prototype python application using django (frontend) + celery (backend) to collate all SaaS licenses under a user identity.
- Deployed the product into production hosted on a GCP kubernetes cluster with CI/CD + monitoring.
- Ensured the internet facing frontend as well as the backend met our security standards and passed regular penetration tests.
- Refactored the application model into a graph-like structure so we could relate anything to anything and capture a wider range of things including cloud infrastructure.
- The product is a valued tool for the business answering queries regarding ownership, highlighting issues and supporting automations. It has saved over £1M in license costs and reduced security risks.

Tester Sep 2018 - Jan 2019 Felinesoft

Felinesoft was a small consultancy offering SaaS CRM Software solutions via Microsoft CRM.

Up to this point I had being working as a contractor for 20 years involving a lot of travel and decided I wanted to be more permanently based in Bristol.

Developer

Aug 2017 - June 2018

Boxfusion (for CIMA)

 Implemented various web service integrations into their clients (CIMA) CRM system

Developer

Aug 2013 - July 2017

Cancer Research

- Built integrations for their data suppliers to supply feeds into their CRM system
- Designed and built RESTful APIs over the CRM to allow easy integration to their Events Management system
- Developed an internal Enterprise Service Bus using TIBCO after evaluating other similar products

Developer

Mar 2013 - July 2013

Customer Systems

- Extended integrations (to World Pay) for Dyson's CRM system.
- Built course application integrations for CIMA

Data Analyst

Mar 2010 - Jan 2013

Research Councils

- Homogenised 7 organisations onto a new common system involving over a 100 entities with high volumes of data.
- Developed a data validation engine to speed up the turn around of iterations.
- Developed ETL integrations to their data warehouse.

Integration Developer

June 2009 - Feb 2010

Logica

- Developed integrations for the governments vetting and barring scheme.
- · Added protective monitoring to record the accessing of sensitive data.

INTERESTS

Jazz ≅ Recreational Maths 🔥 Rowing